Guide to the M. L. Rosenthal Papers ca. 1930-1996 MSS 45
New York University Libraries, Publisher
The M. L. Rosenthal Papers ca. 1930-1996
The M.L. Rosenthal Papers
50 linear feet (36 boxes)
Rosenthal, M. L. (Macha Louis), 1917-
Macha Louis Rosenthal (1917-1996), poet, critic, editor, and teacher, was born in Washington, D. C. With an M.A. from the University of Chicago, he came to New York University where he earned his Ph.D. (1949) and was a professor of English until 1996. He also served as director of the Poetics Institute at NYU. Besides publishing numerous books of criticism, collections of verse and contributing poetry, articles and reviews to The New Yorker, Poetry, the Spectator, he served in the U.S. Cultural Exchange Program from 1961-1980 and was visiting specialist to Germany, Pakistan, Romania, Poland, and Bulgaria, Italy and France. He also was poetry editor of The Nation, the Humanist, and Present Tense and edited various anthologies of poetry.
Provenance
The M. L. Rosenthal Papers were donated in October 1996 by Victoria Rosenthal. The initial organization of the collection was done by Sally M. Gall, student and colleague of Rosenthal.
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers.
Historical/Biographical Note:
Macha Louis Rosenthal, poet, critic, editor, and teacher, was born on March 14, 1917 in Washington, D. C. He took his B.A. (1937) and M.A. (1938) degrees at the University of Chicago. On January 7, 1939, he married Victoria Himmelstein with whom he had three children: David, Alan, and Laura. From 1939 to 1945, he taught as an instructor in English at Michigan State University. In 1946, he was hired as an instructor at New York University, where he earned his Ph.D. in 1949. In 1961, he served in the U.S. Cultural Exchange Program and was visiting specialist to Germany; in 1965, to Pakistan; in 1966, to Romania, Poland, and Bulgaria, and in 1980, to Italy and France. In 1974, he was a visiting poet in Israel. From 1977 to 1979 he served as director of the Poetics Institute at New York University where he was a professor of English until 1996. He was a fellow of the American Council of Learned Societies and twice won Guggenheim Fellowships (1960-1964). He contributed poems, articles, and reviews to such leading journals as The New Yorker, the New Statesman, Poetry, the Spectator (London), ELH, and the Quarterly Review of Literature; he also served, from 1956-1961, as poetry editor of The Nation, from 1970-1978 as poetry editor of the Humanist, and from 1973-1990 as poetry editor of Present Tense. He published numerous books of criticism and collections of verse and edited various anthologies of poetry. M. L. Rosenthal died on July 21, 1996.
Scope and Content Note
The M. L. Rosenthal Papers are a part of the Fales Library/Special Collections, New York University. The Fales Library is the primary special collections division of the NYU libraries, housing over 200,000 volumes of English and American literature from 1700 to the present. Strengths of the collection include the development of the English and American novel, with an emphasis on the Gothic and the Victorian novel.
The archival portion of the M. L. Rosenthal Papers is comprised of the correspondence, manuscripts and subject files of many notable literary figures; the manuscripts and business/production files for Rosenthal's scholarly books, essays, poetry, reviews, and lectures; journals, offprints, and other printed materials; biographical material; photographs; and audiovisual material. The M. L. Rosenthal Papers contains a comprehensive collection of the early to late literary career of M. L. Rosenthal. Sally M. Gall's original organization of Rosenthal's papers was preserved as much as possible.
SERIES DESCRIPTION
SERIES I: Correspondence: contains 2 boxes of correspondence with such important literary figures as William Carlos Williams, Ted Hughes, Robert Creeley, Christopher Grieve, Laura Riding Jackson, Muriel Rukeyser, and many others. It also contains family correspondence with Rosenthal's wife, Vicki, and his two sons, David and Alan.
SERIES II: Manuscripts: contains 3 boxes of manuscripts by Paul Blackburn, Kenneth Burke, Ramon Guthrie, Ted Hughes, Muriel Rukeyser, James Schevill, Grace Schulman, Theodore Weiss, and William Carlos Williams, among many others.
SERIES III: Subject Files: contains 2 boxes of subject files providing background information, notes, reviews, articles, etc. on the literary figures with which Rosenthal corresponded or studied. Subseries B contains 2 boxes of general subject files on various topics of interest for Rosenthal.
SERIES IV: M. L. Rosenthal's Writing: contains 6 boxes of Rosenthal's manuscripts and other book-related files, arranged chronologically by book. All materials related to each book are kept together, including later editions. Subseries B contains 4 boxes of Rosenthal's manuscripts for poems, essays, reviews and lectures, often in several drafts.
SERIES V: Printed Material: subseries A contains 2 boxes of the journals and other publications that include entries by Rosenthal. Subseries B contains 2 boxes of offprints and other miscellaneous printed material by authors other than Rosenthal.
SERIES VI: Biographical Material: contains 8 boxes of biographical materials including juvenilia, college materials, notebooks, teaching notes, syllabi, student papers, and other course-related materials pertaining to Rosenthal's teaching career. It also contains programs and playbills from various events he attended, information and souvenirs from places he traveled, and paperwork from grants and programs for which he applied. Box 1 of Series VI contains the most important biographical material, including articles about M. L. Rosenthal. Box 7 of Series 6 is a small gray box holding Rosenthal's address books and planners. Box 8 of Series 6 contains accretions from Rosenthal's office at the English Department and materials found in Rosenthal's books while cataloguing them at Fales.
SERIES VII: Production Files: contains 2 boxes of production files for several of Rosenthal's books, arranged alphabetically by book title.
SERIES VIII: Photographs: contains 1 small black box of photographs of Rosenthal, his family, and other miscellaneous group photographs.
SERIES IX: Audiovisual Files: contains 1 letter box of cassette tapes of readings and other miscellaneous recording, reel-to-reel tape, and one microfilm. [Research copies may not be available for these materials yet. Check with the Fales archivist.]
OVERSIZE: There is 1 flat oversize box that contains oversize materials from series 5 and 6.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading.
The files are grouped into 9 series and subdivided into subseries.
Access Points
Subject Names:
Rosenthal, M.L. (Macha Louis), 1917-; Williams, William Carlos, 1883-1963; Hughes, Ted, 1930-; Creeley, Robert, 1926-; MacDiarmid, Hugh, 1892-; Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-; Blackburn, Paul; Guthrie, Ramon, 1896-; Schevill, James Erwin, 1920-; Schulman, Grace.; Weiss, Theodore J., 1919-; Jackson, Laura (Riding), 1901-; Burke, Kenneth, 1897-; Amis, Kingsley; Dickey, James; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-; Kermode, Frank; Kinsella, Thomas; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972
Subject Organizations:
New York University
Subject Topics:
Authors, American.; Poets, American.; American literature--20th century.; American poetry--20th century.; Literature--Study and teaching.; American poetry--20th century--History and criticism.; Authors and publishers--United States.
Subject Places:
Document Types:
Manuscripts for publication; Correspondence; Notebooks; Reviews; Articles; Journals (periodicals); Lecture notes; Syllabi; Ephemera; Juvenilia; Address Books; Photographs; Audiotape
Other Names:
Container List
[The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.]
- Series I: Correspondence
  - A, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abse, Dannie, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alvarez, Al, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Amichai, Yehuda, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Amis, Kingsley, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - B, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Blackburn, Paul, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Boutelle, Annie, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brooke-Rose, Christine, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Burke, France, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Burke, Kenneth, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bush, Douglas, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - C, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Capouya, Emile, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cargill, Oscar, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Carmi, T., undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ciardi, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Clarke, Austin, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Creeley, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - D, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Davie, Donald, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Dicker, Harold, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dickey, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Donoghue, Denis, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Duncan, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - E, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Eberhart, Richard, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Eliot, T. S., undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - F, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Fauchereau, Serge, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Fearing, Kenneth, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Feirstein, Fred, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ferlinghetti, Laurence, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Finlay, Ian Hamilton, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Fueloep-Miller, Erika, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - G, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Gall, Sally M., undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Galler, David, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Ginsberg, Allen and Louis, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Greene, David, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Gregory, Horace, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Gregory, Marya, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Grieve, Christopher, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Gover, Philip, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Guthrie, Ramon, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - H, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Hall, Donald, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Harrison, Jim, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Holloway, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Horovitz, Michael, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Hoskins, Katherine, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Hughes, Ted, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Humphries, Rolfe, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - I, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - J, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - K, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Keane, Patrick, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Kermode, Frank, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Kinnell, Galway, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Kinsella, Thomas, undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Kizer, Carolyn, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - L, undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Laing, Alexander, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Laing, Dilys, undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Laughlin, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Levertov, Denise, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Lowell, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - M, undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Mc, undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - MacManus, Frank, undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Mann, Thomas, undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - May, James Boyer, undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Merwin, W. S., undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Montague, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Moore, Marianne, undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Mottram, Eric, undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Muir, Edwin, undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Murphy, Richard, undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - N, undated (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Nemerov, Howard, undated (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - O, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Olney, James, undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Olson, Charles, undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - P, undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Pound, Ezra, undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Q, undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - R, undated (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Redgrove, Peter, undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Rago, Henry, undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Riding, Laura (Jackson), undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Ridler, Anne, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Rudman, Mark, undated (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, undated (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - S, undated (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Schevill, James, undated (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Schulman, Grace, undated (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Shapiro, Karl, undated (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Smith, A. J. M., undated (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Spender, Stephen, undated (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Swenson, May, undated (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - T, undated (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Tomlinson, Charles, undated (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - V, undated (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - W, undated (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Weber, Richard, undated (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Weiss, Theodore, undated (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Whittemore, Reed, undated (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Wilbur, Richard, undated (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Williams, Jonathan, undated (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Williams, William Carlos, undated (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Wright, David, undated (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - XYZ, undated (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Chinese correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Family correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Italian correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Correspondence from MLR, undated (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Correspondence from MLR to Vicky, undated (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Correspondence from MLR to Vicky, undated (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Unidentified correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 120)
- Series II: Manuscripts
  - A, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abse, Dannie, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alvarez, Al, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Amichai, Yehuda, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - B, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Barnstone, Willis, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Barnstone, Willis, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Blackburn, Paul, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Burke, France, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Burke, Kenneth, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Burnshaw, Stanley, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - C, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cameron, Kenneth Neill, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cargill, Oscar, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Carmi, T., undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Creeley, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - D, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Davie, Donald, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Diamond, Stanley, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Dicker, Harold, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Doyle, Charles, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Duncan, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Eberhart, Richard, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Evans, George (ed.), undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Evans, George (ed.), undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Evans, George (ed.), undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Evans, George (ed.), undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - F, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Fields, Scott, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Feirstein, Fred, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Feirstein, Fred, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - G, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Gall, Sally M., undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Gall, Sally M., undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Ginsberg, Allen, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Grover, Philip, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Guthrie, Ramon, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Guthrie, Ramon, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - H, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Harrison, Jim, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Horowitz, Michael, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Hughes, Ted, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - I, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - J, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - K, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Keane, Patrick, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Kinsella, Thomas, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - L, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Laing, Alexander, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Laing, Dilys, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - M, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Mc, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Merriam, Eve, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Montague, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Murphy, Richard, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - N, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Nemerov, Harold, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - O, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - P, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Pagis, Dan, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Poetry Group (1971-72), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Q, undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - R, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Raimes, James, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Redgrove (the group), undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Redgrove, Peter, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Rosenthal, David, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Rudnick, Raphael, undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - S, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Schevill, James, undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Schulman, Grace, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, undated (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, undated (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Seferis, George, undated (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Smith, A. J. M., undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Sommer, undated (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Stanford, Ann, undated (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Stevens, Wallace, undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - T, undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Tomlinson, Charles, undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - V, undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - W, undated (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Weber, Richard, undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Weiss, Theodore, undated (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Williams, William Carlos, undated (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Wolf, Leonard, undated (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Wright, David, undated (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - XYZ, undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Unidentified mss., undated (Box 3, Folder 91)
- Series III: Subject Files
  - Subseries A: writers and artists
    - A, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abse, Dannie, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alvarez, Al, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Auden, W. H., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - B, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Berryman, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Betjeman, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Blackburn, Paul, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bloom, Harold, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Borges, J. L., undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Brecht, Bertold, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Burke, France, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Burke, Kenneth, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - C, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Capouya, Emile, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Cargill, Oscar, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Creeley, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - D, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Dickinson, Emily, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Dicker, Harold, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Dickey, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Duncan, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - E, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Eberhart, Richard, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Eliot, T. S., undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Eliot, T. S., undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - F, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Finlay, Ian Hamilton, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Frost, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - G, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Gall, Sally M., undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Ghalib, Mirza, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Ginsberg, Allen and Louis, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Graves, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Gregory, Horace, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Gregory, Lady, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Grieve, Christopher, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Gurthrie, Ramon, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - H, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Harrison, Jim, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Holloway, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Horovitz, Michael, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Hoskins, Katherine, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Hughes, Ted, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - I, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - J, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Joyce, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - K, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Kavanagh, Patrick, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Kinnell, Galway, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Kinsella, Thomas, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Kizer, Carolyn, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - L, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Laing, Alexander, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Laing, Dilys, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Laughlin, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Lawrence, D. H., undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Levertov, Denise, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Lowell, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - M, undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Mc, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - MacNeice, Louise, undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Merriam, Eve, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Merwin, W. S., undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Montague, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Mottram, Eric, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Moore, Marianne, undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Muir, Edwin, undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Muir, Kenneth, undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Murphy, Richard, undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - N, undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Nemerov, Howard, undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - O, undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Olson, Charles, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - P, undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Parra, Nicanor, undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Plath, Sylvia, undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Pound, Ezra, undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Pound, Ezra, undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Pound, Ezra, undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Q, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - R, undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Rago, Henry, undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Redgrove, Peter, undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Riding, Laura (Jackson), undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Roethke, Theodore, undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Rosenthal, David, undated (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Rudman, Mark, undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Rudnick, Raphael, undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel, undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - S, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Schevill, James, undated (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Schulman, Grace, undated (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Scott, Winfield Townley, undated (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Seferis, George, undated (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Shapiro, Karl, undated (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Shelton, Richard, undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Simpson, Louis, undated (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Smith, A. J. M., undated (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Spender, Stephen, undated (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Stendhal, undated (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Stevens, Wallace, undated (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - T, undated (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Thomas, Dylan, undated (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - V, undated (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - W, undated (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Walker, Ted, undated (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Weiss, Theodore, undated (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Whittemore, Reed, undated (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Wilbur, Richard, undated (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Williams, Tennessee, undated (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Williams, William Carlos, undated (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Wilson, Edmund, undated (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Wright, David, undated (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Wright, James, undated (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - XYZ, undated (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Yeats, W. B., undated (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Unidentified subjects, undated (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Subseries B: General
    - Advice to PMLA, etc., undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Aesthetics, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - African literature, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - American literature (general), undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Anthologies (poetry), undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Anthologies (war poetry), undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Art, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Background on pre-modern poets, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Background on prose writers, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - BBC, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - BBC broadcast and other radio, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Behavior, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bibliographies, reading lists, etc., undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Brighton festival, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Children's work, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)